# **DAVIDE GHIOTTO**

January, 2022

(VI) Italy | dghiotto.careers@gmail.com | linkedin: davide-ghiotto | github: davide97g | portfolio: davideghiotto.it

### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

#### **CARRIER PROFILE**

Full Stack Developer with 30 months of experience implementing custom Angular/Vuejs Web Applications and core Java microservices, for large scale use in the banking sector and for certification authorities companies. Developed reusable components and effective models to keep the pace with continuous delivery of high quality products. Managed a massive database migration activity.

Core competences include: Angular, Vuejs, Java, Node.js, web API, TypeScript, Firebase, JavaScript, SQL, MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, Spring, Git, HTML, CSS, Sass.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Namirial

October 2021 to present

R & D Developer

Full stack R&D developer building cross-platform applications with Vuejs 3, Electron and .Net.

### Zucchetti S.p.A

April 2021 to July 2021

Data Scientist

Built an online interactive platform for the introduction of data science topics inside the company. Developed custom algorithms for time-series analysis and unsupervised learning

- Organized the architecture for a wide online library of machine-learning algorithms implemented in JavaScript
- Developed custom machine-learning algorithms for time-series analysis and unsupervised learning, targeting the specific problems of the company

## Reply S.p.A - Cluster & Core Financial Services

Nov 2019 to Oct 2021

Full Stack Developer & Database Manager

Developed complete Angular Web Applications, integrated with backend Java API, in a microservice oriented architecture, in order to build a large scale platform capable of handling the complexity of financial services world.

Managed a massive database migration to a SQL Server environment.

Implemented high quality code to speed up further developments in a continuous delivery environment.

- Created a generalized conceptual model to efficiently handle user interactions and data flow leading to an uniformed solution capable of avoid potential error situations and repetitive work
- Implemented a decentralized error handling strategy to avoid single point of failure with an increased reliability of the system
- ullet Improved data retrieval time through careful analysis and optimization of database's requests along with asynchronous client-side code

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### Atoma World Project

October 2021 to present

NFT-based game

Developed a startup project based on NFTs called **Atoma** which architecture is organized as follows:

- Frontend: Angular Webapp hosted by Firebase with CI thanks to Github Actions
- Backend: Nodejs Express Server hosted on Heroku for the REST API
- Smart Contracts: C++ smart-contracts deployed on the WAX Blockchain for the in-game functionalities

## Ultra Gymnasium

September 2020 to September 2021

Angular PWA

Developed a fully functional progressive web app in Angular for handling data coming from gyms context: creating a digital workout, reporting statistics, track live workout data. The frontend was made in Angular and hosted on Firebase. The Node.js server deployed on Heroku.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Web technologies: Angular, Vuejs, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Sass
- Backend technologies: Nodejs, Java, Python, Spring
- Database: MongoDB, MySQL, POSTGRES, ORACLE
- Cloud Platform: Firebase, Google Cloud Platform, Heroku
- Data Science: R, Python, Pandas, Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-learn
- Versioning: Git, Github, Bitbucket

# **EDUCATION**

Master's Degree Data Science 110L/110 Bachelor's Degree Computer Science 110L/110 Highschool Graduation

University of Study of Padua 2019-2021 University of Study of Padua 2016-2019

Liceo Scientifico Statale G.B. Quadri 2011-2016

# **CERTIFICATES**

87/100

• **B2 First**, 2015

## **OTHER SKILLS**

Languages English: professional proficiency. Italian: native.